Aleksandr Khriukin

Full Stack Web Developer

Portland, OR, 97201, United States +15038909328 · <u>hryukinaleksand@gmail.com</u>

😑 <u>LinkedIn, Github,</u> <u>Personal web site</u>

Skills

JavaScript

TypeScript

React

Node.js

Next.js

HTML

CSS

MongoDB

Docker

Git

Python

Unit Testing

CI/CD

Jenkins

Microsoft Azure

Google Cloud Platform

REST APIs

Frontend Development

Backend Development

Full Stack Development

Search Engine Optimization

Code Review

Agile Methodologies

Teamwork

Languages

English

Russian

Summary

Experienced Web Developer adept in all stages of advanced web development. Knowledgeable in user interface, testing, and debugging processes. Able to effectively self manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

Employment History

Full Stack Web Developer, Revain LLC, Full time

October 2020 - August 2023

- Developed, tested, deployed, and maintained a blockchain based review platform and auxiliary microservices.
- Built responsive web pages using React.js and Next.js.
- Created and maintained an API server for a media content storage using Python, which led to a 30% cost reduction compared to using a third party storage.
- Designed, optimized and integrated databases with applications.
- Provided effective troubleshooting and remediation for web applications, detected and eliminated errors.
- Performed API integration with third party services.
- Ensured web application performance and search engine optimization, analyzed and improved software speed and efficiency which resulted in a 40% page load time reduction and a 45% growth in search appearances.
- Reviewed source code for compliance with standards and best practices.
- Determined time frames for completing tasks and project milestones.
- Actively participated in planning new features and developing the project roadmap
- Effectively interacted with colleagues, designers, project managers and other team members.

Frontend Developer, Healthy Bones Australia, Contract

August 2023 - October 2023

Implemented responsive web pages, complex logic for UI components, data presentation components (graphs, charts, tables), API facade for data retrieval, internationalization, and authentication.

Education

Bachelor of Software Engineering, Omsk State Technical University

September 2017 - August 2021